{
    "id": "23976a8ce85d4cb4b10e0967054eaf81",
    "title": "Sentence Completion Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "If I had completed my studies, I …………………… a better job.",
            "description": "In the third conditional we use a past perfect tense in the if-clause and would/could/might have + past participle in the main clause.",
            "answers": [
                "could find",
                "can find",
                "could have found"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "b9602734fab744c8ab62ae17afccf0df"
        },
        {
            "question": "Get that cat ............................. the piano.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "from",
                "off",
                "up"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "15be2e1c7cf0415a9b3790045a88e162"
        },
        {
            "question": "You can eat as much as you ……………………",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "will want",
                "want",
                "wanted"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "7e3df379992c4eb3bcbc6129dfe750c0"
        },
        {
            "question": "She said that she ............................ coming.",
            "description": "When the main verb is in the past tense, the verb in the subordinate clause too will be in the past tense.",
            "answers": [
                "is",
                "was",
                "has been"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "9b5d5ad582284d62a925dd85176dce0b"
        },
        {
            "question": "……………………. she tried, she could not solve the problem.",
            "description": "Fronted adjectives/adverbs are possible in a structure with as or though.",
            "answers": [
                "Hard as",
                "Hard though",
                "Though hard"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "ca3957ce8ff84485b98477695f17a5fc"
        },
        {
            "question": "The show was ……………………..",
            "description": "The present participle shows the action or people that cause the feeling. ",
            "answers": [
                "interesting",
                "interested",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "7d60f7e0d50249efabb89acd8b14b9e3"
        },
        {
            "question": "He asked me what ................................. doing there.",
            "description": "The subject goes before the verb in indirect questions.",
            "answers": [
                "was I",
                "I was",
                "I am"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "702b001523da47f1a4bf551d604c0d06"
        },
        {
            "question": "Hardly ................................ sat down to rest, when someone knocked on the door.",
            "description": "Inversion is used when a sentence starts with only or hardly or seldom.",
            "answers": [
                "I had",
                "Had I",
                "I did"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "1a253c1565374388954726bd95acfd2d"
        },
        {
            "question": "Seldom ................................ seen such a mess.",
            "description": "Inversion is used when a sentence starts with only or hardly or seldom.",
            "answers": [
                "I have",
                "have I",
                "did I"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "51de64f93f6744bf9e74b616e7fd6019"
        },
        {
            "question": "'I don't want to do.' '......................... do I.'",
            "description": "After a negative statement we can add another negative statement with neither or nor. ",
            "answers": [
                "So",
                "Neither",
                "Nor"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "83dab3f3c4cf4d3d81e790d392d85c4e"
        },
        {
            "question": "We cannot go out ................................... it rains.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "as soon as",
                "as long as",
                "as far as"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "2490afe038fb40bfb2e5a867f6962f09"
        },
        {
            "question": "I would rather you .............................. now.",
            "description": "We use a past tense with a present meaning after would rather. ",
            "answers": [
                "leave",
                "left",
                "had left"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "3878eecbe207447ab4c72ab03879db80"
        }
    ]
}